[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 3]
My Lord,
turn it.
I meant turn the map, not you.
She's planning to flee.
She is indeed planning to flee.
But she intends
to clean out our Demons' Valley
before she runs away.
Why does she want to steal carrots?
That's ginseng.
She even wants to steal
the mushrooms, too.
That's lingzhi.
You must protect
this snow lotus at all costs.
Please rest assured, My Lord.
The snow lotus is absolutely safe.
Because what Xiao Yao wants to steal is
the cordyceps.
She is acting way too wildly.
I must give her a serious punishment.
A serious punishment.
There's one more thing.
The red-thread demon
lost a pair of red matchmaking threads.
I've already checked
all the little demons,
but so far,
there's been no mismatched couple.
Those matchmaking threads are
no big deal.
Why are you here?
Are you looking for this?
My h-head hurts.
I feel so dizzy.
I'm afraid I won't be able
to attend classes for the next few days.
Is that so?
Let me treat you.
What on earth have I done to offend you?
Why are you teasing me like this?
So you noticed that I was teasing you.
You...
Before the second phase ends,
you should just
have a good rest in this hut.
Don't go to class anymore.
Hold on.
How long will the second phase last?
It could be as short as 3 to 5 days,
or as long as 10 days to half a month,
depending on how well we're in sync.
No, no, no. Wait!
I don't agree with this.
You told me to learn quickly
and return to the human world,
but now you're confining me here?
If you don't let me go, I'll go anyway.
I don't believe
you'll follow me every day,
giving up your cultivation time.
How about this?
Let's make a deal.
I'll allow you to attend classes
on Moon-Gazing Terrace,
but you must focus on your cultivation.
If you can make it,
I'll give you anything marked on this map.
As much as you want.
For real?
For real.
You just need to remember
not to cause trouble again
or mess up the order of Demons' Valley.
That's a deal.
This time, I must teach that bamboo
a good lesson.
Digging up some bamboo shoots
won't hurt him much.
If humans got him,
they'd uproot the whole bamboo!
Yeah.
Xiao Yao, listen.
Humans are terrifying, you know?
Back then, they claimed
to love beautiful, blooming flowers,
but they always cut off our roots,
making us unable to grow anymore.
I endured decades
of trials and tribulations
and just gained consciousness,
only to nearly get killed by humans.
To survive
and keep humans from discovering me,
I had to
shed my petals one by one,
struggling until I could transform
into human form.
Humans are two-faced
and ruthless.
My mom said
that they fed and kept us well,
but every once in a while,
they'd put red ribbons
on the best of our ancestors
and take them away.
Not until one day
when my mother witnessed
my grandfather being butchered by humans
did I realize
that our ancestors who never returned
had all been slaughtered by humans!
Yeah!
After that,
my mother kept me starving every day.
Sometimes I felt so dizzy due to hunger
and couldn't even see my mother clearly.
But she said she was trying to save me.
One year, when humans suffered famine,
that family sent us all
to the butcher's place.
I was terrified at that time!
It was my mother.
My mother frantically charged forward
and rushed out,
risking her life to shove them away
and even smashing the pigpen,
so I could finally escape.
Later,
I wandered around aimlessly
until I ate some divine herbs.
I had my powers grow gradually
and finally transform
into human form.
Someday,
after I drink the Yuli Spring,
I will find those humans
and seek justice for my family.
Mm!
Actually,
humans,
just like demons,
also have good guys
and bad ones among them.
Humans are more terrifying, though.
You three...
My bamboo shoots!
Run!
Run quickly!
Luoluo! Dali!
Come over here!
I-If I catch you,
I'll...
You...
Stop right there!
Stop running!
Come here!
Stop...
What is her true form again?
It's a bird.
No, it's a snake!
♪ My heart braves countless tribulations ♪
♪ Seeking the prophecy of fate ♪
♪ Memories are flickering ♪
♪ Our fingertips touched,
and then passed ♪
♪ Binding silent wishes,
witnessed by the heaven and earth ♪
♪ I'm only waiting for you ♪
I told you to take care of yourself
and not to drag me into your mess.
♪ In a breath,
travel over millions of years ♪
But what did you do?
You still acted recklessly
and caused trouble.
♪ To rewrite it ♪
I will certainly punish you severely.
We share feelings and senses.
♪ The obsession of my life ♪
Punishing me is punishing yourself.
♪ Has never perished
in the reincarnation ♪
♪ At the very beginning of all worlds,
I'd give up everything ♪
♪To reverse time and space
just to find my most beloved ♪
♪ Even if I have to lose my love again ♪
♪ I only wish
to return to our first meeting ♪
♪ Let the restricted longing ♪
♪ Break the boundary of heaven and earth ♪
♪ One thought turned love
into a fated calamity ♪
♪ If we pray in tears ♪
How did you get hurt?
♪ In the vast mortal world ♪
What do you think?
♪ Just to see you ♪
♪ Once again ♪
That left a wound on my face!
Hey,
it's fine that you got wounded,
but don't drag me down with you.
Which matters more,
your face or your life?
Life matters.
But if life is not in danger,
then face is certainly most important.
Didn't you feel pain when dropping me?
Those...
Those! Those over there.
What are they?
Qiongqi,
Ao Hen,
Tengshe.
They all look awesome and formidable.
Compared to you,
who would be stronger?
There's no chance to compare.
They were all ancient mythical beasts.
They perished in the war against humans.
To commemorate them,
the demons carved their images
on the mountains.
Their physical bodies
already perished 10,000 years ago.
So humans and demons
have been fighting for so long.
What?
My Lord,
I specially made
this roasted bamboo shoot for you.
Please give it a try.
It's really palatable.
How does it taste?
Not bad, huh?
Mm.
Please don't keep this scar.
It will heal soon.
My Lord,
could you teach me
that bubble spell?
As long as you practice diligently,
you'll pick up
way more than this in the future.
But
the progress in class is too slow.
When will I be able to master it?
As long as you're focused on studying
instead of digging bamboo shoots,
tricking turtles for their shells,
or coveting wolf fur and deer antlers,
you'll eventually get the hang of them
with daily practice.
I have a question for you.
Is it true that when you reach
the highest level of cultivation,
you'll become free from all desires
with no demand for food or drinks anymore?
Sure.
Then I'd rather not cultivate too well.
Otherwise, everything would taste bland
when I return to the human realm.
That would be such a loss for me.
You look so handsome when you smile.
Why don't you smile more often?
Is it because you've
suffered too much in the past?
The eight sufferings of life,
I've experienced them all.
What eight sufferings?
Birth, aging, sickness, death.
Separation from the beloved.
Prolonged resentment.
Unfulfilled desires.
Inability to let go.
You've been through all of them?
Have a good rest.
Looks like I made him recall
something sad again.
This old demon.
Today,
we're going to talk
about the nine-tailed fox first.
It's a fox-shaped beast
with four legs and nine tails.
It devours humans.
Eating their flesh
can ward off evil.
Do you know that?
The red-thread demon's...
His red matchmaking threads are
still missing.
He's almost losing his mind
due to anxiety.
Really?
So you know
about the red matchmaking threads, too?
It's common knowledge.
Don't tell me you don't know.
Of course I know.
The red matchmaking threads
have three phases.
In the first phase,
the couple cannot be
more than 10 feet apart.
In the second phase,
the couple shares feelings and senses.
As for the third phase...
Do you really know?
Next,
let's move on
to ancient sayings.
"Water flows from high rocks
and runs westward
to merge into the river."
Pair cultivation?
What is pair cultivation?
Seems like you're giving up
on untying the red threads.
I don't want to do pair cultivation!
No pair cultivation! I refuse!
How can we untie the threads
without doing it?
I know everything now.
Don't try to take advantage of me.
What do you even know?
You planned this in the first place,
all for this final step, right?
Shady demon, old monster.
You wicked demon!
You're so evil!
You were the one who wrapped
the red threads around my hand,
causing all this trouble.
I...
I still refuse to do pair cultivation!
I don't want it.
I don't want pair cultivation.
I'm an unmarried damsel.
I won't do pair cultivation with you!
The sooner we finish,
the sooner we break free.
Let me go!
Let go of me!
No pair cultivation!
I refuse.
Are you ready?
I'm asking if you're ready.
No, no, no.
I'm not ready. I'm not.
I'm not prepared.
The third phase
requires both parties
bound by the red threads to work together
and master the same spell.
This is demons' pair cultivation.
Just this?
What did you think it was?
Well, then...
Which spell will we practice?
You're no more than a beginner.
And my power is still recovering.
Let's practice the simplest one,
the Fire Technique.
Okay.
I'll teach you the incantation now.
Do I have to recite an incantation?
Can't you just transfer
your spiritual power to me?
Then I'd pull it off right away...
Try again.
I got it. It's the right hand.
Once more.
She's naughty and unruly.
For rapid cultivation,
one must experience
joy, anger, sorrow, and fear
to really master it.
I can't get the hang of it.
It's such a simple spell,
yet you're so lame,
failing to learn
after hundreds of attempts.
Forget about demons;
even among humans,
you're a complete fool.
Utterly hopeless.
Who are you calling a fool?
I think you're the incompetent one.
You can't even break a single red thread!
And you call yourself Demon Lord?
You should step down
and let someone else take over.
Anger achieved. Good.
Stop there.
Try again.
There's fire! I've mastered it!
Joy achieved as well.
I told you I couldn't pick it up.
You're fooling me.
Look,
even God is not on your side.
Sorrow achieved.
What happens
if we fail at pair cultivation?
Hey.
Hey!
What do you think will happen?
Don't you know the result?
I don't know!
If we can't untie the threads,
you and I will become one.
You'll end up in my stomach.
No! No! No!
No!
Fear achieved as well.
I've got it! Look!
I've mastered it.
It doesn't extinguish.
They've been removed! Finally!
Fear is
the best way to control people's minds.
Only when they fear you
will they respect you.
When the full moon rises,
I will take you to have a test
in the human world.
Whether you're focused on your studies now
will determine if you can survive that.
Xiao Yao,
don't you know humans the best?
Luoluo and I will rely on you then.
Thank you.
Any unusual human activities?
The Feiyu Guards are
encouraging human demon hunters
to search for demons
with high spiritual power.
They say,
regardless of status or background,
whoever captures a great demon
will receive generous bounties
and high official positions.
This is clearly aimed at you, My Lord.
Now that your wounds are healing,
you must train hard
and stop focusing on Xiao Yao.
A battle with the Feiyu Guard
is inevitable.
There's no need to avoid.
With my current cultivation,
I can deal with them easily.
Xiao Mu.
What has Hei Wu been up to lately?
Hei Wu?
He hasn't made any moves yet.
But his subordinate Wu Huan is
arranging for all the minor demons
at Moon-Gazing Terrace
to take a test in the human realm.
Take a test.
A reward.
This is my personal possession.
You will soon
take a test in the human realm.
If you encounter danger,
hold this jade pendant tightly
and call me with your thoughts.
Will you definitely appear?
Sure, I'll keep you safe.
Okay.
That's all.
As I said,
only in times of danger.
The village below
is called Lantern Village.
Humans think hanging lanterns
can ward off evil
and protect them from demons.
Utterly ridiculous.
This village
is the testing ground for your trials.
What you need to do
is to find a household,
then
frighten a child to tears,
and bring back a pillow.
And you'll pass the test.
That's too difficult.
And we have to take a pillow?
They're all asleep.
I mean, taking their pillow, really?
Remember, no matter what happens,
before the first rooster crows,
you must return here.
Understand?
Got it.
Yes.
What if we can't make it back?
If there are no questions,
the test begins.
A head start?
Xiao Yao, wait for us!
Xiao Yao!
My Lord,
when do we make our move?
No rush.
Catching these few minor demons
would be a waste of such a big operation.
This pillow-stealing folk trick
is something I mastered as a child.
Fellow demons,
farewell.
Xiao Yao!
Xiao Yao.
I...
Xiao Yao,
just thinking about our past experiences
makes our legs go weak—
let alone
trying to scare humans.
It's fine. Humans aren't scary.
Go on, hurry up.
Look,
Luoluo is so scared
he's practically speaking pig language.
Xiao Yao,
aren't you the best
at dealing with humans?
Could you help us two?
Please.
You two wait for me here.
Thank you, Xiao Yao.
Hurry, hurry.
Let's hide, come on.
Why isn't she back yet?
Could something have happened?
Impossible.
Xiao Yao is so clever.
Nothing will go wrong.
Xiao Yao!
Got it.
Thank you.
Let's hurry and go.
Let's go.
You go ahead.
I need to go back for my pillow.
-We'll wait for you.
-Xiao Yao, be careful.
Why did the demon-subduing talisman
mistake me for a demon just now?
Could it be true, as Hong Ye said,
that I've been tainted
with demonic energy,
which will bring deadly trouble
to my dad and me
and make me unable
to return to the human realm?
Help! Someone, come quickly!
Catch demons! Catch demons!
Luoluo!
Come here quickly!
Come here!
Where are they?
Where?
Over here!
Hurry!
Coming! Coming!
Catch him! Quick!
Don't let him escape!
Don't let him get away!
Quick! Over here!
It's over here!
Catch him!
Where do you think you're going?
Tie him up!
Hold him down!
Pin him down!
Tie him up!
Hit him!
Beat him!
Xiao Yao!
Xiao Yao! Luoluo...
Luoluo has been captured!
Go that way.
No humans are there.
What about Luoluo?
I'll figure something out. Go.
Where do you think you can go?
Run if you can!
Behave yourself!
See if you dare to run again!
Look at his fat face and big ears.
Eating him will surely be nutritious.
Leave the pig ears to me.
We've got something
to go with our drinks now.
He's still grunting here.
What is this?
Pillow.
Sir.
Two pillows.
Remember, doing too much
leads to more mistakes.
Being too showy will also cost you points.
Bamboo.
I asked for one,
yet you gave me two.
Lowest grade.
Well...
I...
Who else hasn't returned?
Xiao Yao.
And Luoluo.
Dali hasn't come back either.
Sir!
Luoluo has been captured by humans!
At this hour,
he must be in the cooking pot by now.
Shut up!
Where's Xiao Yao?
Xiao Yao has gone to save him.
But she's all alone.
There are so many humans.
We need to go help her.
Hurry!
No rush.
The test isn't over yet.
If they want to survive,
they'll have to
rely on their own abilities.
Then they'll really end up in the pot.
At daybreak,
we'll beat drums and gongs
and go to the magistrate's office
for our reward.
Let everyone for miles around know
that we have real skills!
Right!
Yes!
Bring the black dog's blood!
Here.
Xiao Dadan,
your life ends here.
your sins of killing are too great.
Cheating and swindling all day long.
I have come today
to make you pay for your debts.
Nonsense!
I've never killed anyone!
How can you say
my sins of killing are great?
Don't try to play tricks here!
We even catch demons!
Today, I will seek justice from you all!
Spare me!
Have mercy!
We...
We know we were wrong.
We'll never dare to do it again!
Please spare us!
Never again!
I beg you to spare me!
Have mercy!
Please let us go!
Don't let him escape!
Boss!
He's a demon!
Splash him with black dog's blood!
Splash him!
I'm going for it!
Let's go, come on!
My Lord.
This fluorite powder
is colorless and odorless.
Neither humans nor demons can see it.
Only fluorescent light can reveal it.
My Lord, you're indeed brilliant.
This time,
I'll let these minor demons
lead us to the lair of the great demon.
Who hasn't turned in their pillow yet?
Didn't you already submit yours?
Yes.
You three, right?
Just those two.
It was such a simple task,
and you two not only failed to complete it
but also brought trouble upon yourselves.
You're utterly foolish
and beyond redemption!
Go to Pipa Cave immediately,
and without seeing daylight,
reflect for a year.
It's just a test.
We failed, and we'll accept punishment.
Even a beating would be fine.
But why solitary confinement?
Failing the test is a minor issue,
but you two exposed your whereabouts,
putting every fellow disciple in danger.
It's not Xiao Yao's fault.
I'm the one
who brought trouble to everyone.
If I could choose again,
I would still save Luoluo.
In the rules of the Demons' Valley,
isn't life more important than a test?
Please give me a chance
to retake the test.
Since when has the Demons' Valley
ever allowed retakes?
Those rules weren't there
from the beginning.
If I fail the retake...
Yeah.
We're willing to accept any punishment.
Count me in too.
Xiao Yao gave me my pillow,
so I should retake the test as well.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Bring back 3 human heads.
And you'll pass the test.
No harm has ever been done to humans
in the tests of the Demons' Valley,
let alone murder.
Yeah.
This goes against our rules.
Rules?
Retakes aren't in the rules either.
When he was nearly killed just now,
you were willing to risk yourself
rather than kill humans to save him.
Xiao Yao,
since you care so much for humans,
does that mean your loyalty
is no longer with the Demons' Valley?
You smell of the outside world.
What's this?
Footprints.
All the way over there.
Lift your foot.
Lift your foot!
Her footprints.
They're identical.
Where did it come from?
I don't know where I picked it up.
I don't know.
What is this?
This is fluorite powder.
Fluorite powder?
You've left a trail
from the human realm to the demon realm.
Xiao Yao,
are you trying to lead humans
into the Demons' Valley?
What?
So the key to this barrier
is the fluorite powder.
Such a precious land
has been occupied by a bunch of demons.
Truly detestable.
My Lord.
For this expedition,
we have the imperial divine weapon.
Let's end this quickly
by forcing that great demon out.
The divine weapon is too destructive.
Once activated,
this precious land will be ruined.
My Lord.
Since His Majesty
has bestowed the divine weapon,
he wants us to eliminate all evil.
Feiyu Guard!
Execute heaven's will!
Slay demons and vanquish evil!
Form the formation!
W-What's happening?
Xiao Yao!
♪ Desires pile up
across the silent wilderness ♪
Hurry!
Run!
Hurry up!
♪ What in life is truly worth
longing for? ♪
Run quickly!
Get up! Get up!
Xiao Yao, run!
Carry her, Luoluo!
♪ In the cycle of reincarnation,
all beings are boundless and ordinary ♪
Get up!
Run, Xiao Yao!
♪ How can one judge demons
and specters by mere appearances? ♪
Xiao Yao, run!
♪ You forge your obsession
into vermilion around your fingers ♪
You could have escaped in the test.
♪ Crossing ten thousand years
to redeem me in the vast desolation ♪
Why did you come back?
My friends are here.
♪ All beings chase the seas of desire,
weaving nets of greed and hatred ♪
Go.
Hurry!
♪ Only when suffering's carved into
steles do we realize it's karmic burden ♪
♪ Only by burning the heart to ashes
can one end the vanity in karma ♪
Everything is proceeding
according to your plan, Master.
♪ When the world laughs at my obsession ♪
Yes.
♪ Only you can understand
my most fervent faith ♪
♪ Let all beings bloom again,
breaking free from the shackles of fate ♪
♪ In the end, it's not in vain ♪
Take all the demons
to hide in Youning Cave.
Not a single one can be left behind.
♪ In the cycle of reincarnation,
all beings are boundless and ordinary ♪
♪ How can one judge demons
and specters by mere appearances? ♪
You go ahead!
I'll be right back!
Where are you going?
Xiao Yao!
♪ You forge your obsession
into vermilion around your fingers ♪
This place can't be saved. Go quickly!
♪ Crossing ten thousand years
to redeem me in the vast desolation ♪
Listen, homes can be rebuilt.
If you don't leave now, it'll be too late.
♪ All beings chase the seas of desire,
weaving nets of greed and hatred ♪
♪ Only when suffering's carved into
steles do we realize it's karmic burden ♪
♪ Only by burning the heart to ashes
can one end the vanity in karma ♪
♪ When the world laughs at my obsession ♪
♪ Only you can understand
my most fervent faith ♪
♪ Let all beings bloom again,
breaking free from the shackles of fate ♪
♪ In the end, it's not in vain ♪
Master.
This is Zhuyu herbs' last dwelling place.
They've lived here for thousands of years.
They won't leave.
My presence here is enough.
♪ Burned to ashes,
the world vast and desolate ♪
This great demon's power is unfathomable.
Commander Ji, you should withdraw first.
Otherwise, if the battle breaks out,
I'll have to split my focus
to protect you.
Very well.
Be careful, My Lord.
Feiyu Guard, withdraw!
Let's go.
We're going to save the Demons' Valley
from destruction.